

Md Jahid Hasan Khandaker

Full Stack Web Developer



15 Octber 1997



ward 68, DSCC, Tengra, Sarulia, Demra, Dhaka



+8801676123950



github.com/jahidkhandaker



jahid123950@gmail.com

About me -

I would love to involve myself in an organization where I will be able to deliver my skills through my hard work and dedication towards my responsibility. I always try to learn new things to build up my professional skills. In the future, I want to see myself in a place where I can utilize my capabilities to the fullest benefits of the organization and society.

Skills -

OOP (JavaScript, PHP, Java, C++)

HTML, CSS, Bootstrap

React, NodeJS

Laravel Framework

MySQL, MongoDB

Version Control tool (Git, Github)

Microsoft Office(Word, PowerPoint, Excel)

(*)[The skill scale is from 0 (Fundamental Awareness) to 6 (Expert).]

Education

2016 – 2019 Bachelor of Science in Computer Science and Engineering (CSE)

North South University CGPA: 3.03 (out of 4)

2013 - 2015 Higher Secondary School Certificate (HSC)

Dr. Mahbubur Rahman Mollah Collete GPA-5.00 (out of 5) | Board: Dhaka Secondary School Certificate (SSC)

Haji Moazzem Ali High School

GPA-5.00 (out of 5) | Board: Dhaka

Publication

2020

2013

R. Akter, M. J. H. Khandaker, S. Ahmed, M. M. Mugdho and A. K. M. B. Haque, "RFID based Smart Transportation System with Android Application," 2020 2nd International Conference on Innovative Mechanisms for Industry Applications (ICIMIA), Bangalore, India, 2020, pp. 614-619, doi: 10.1109/ICIMIA48430.2020.9074869.

Experience

2020-2021 Junior Executive

Software Development department August 01, 2020 - Present ServiceEngine Ltd. (SEBPO)

Training and Courses

- FTFL AR/VR Training. Organizing by LICT and SEBPO.
- Node with React: Full stack Web Development. [Udemy Course]
- APIs with Laravel: RESTful API with Laravel Build a real API with Laravel. [Udemy Course]

Final Year Project

NSUTS: Smart Transportation System for North South University

Supervised By

AKM Bahalul Haque

Lecturer, Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering

North South University

Project Summary: My final year senior design project is based on the prototype of Radio Frequency Identification (RFID), Global Positioning System (GPS) and android application for authentic fare calculation, real-time tracking and passenger management. The passenger can reserve a seat on a bus, can see the available seat information of a bus and can track the real-time location of the bus through their android application. After getting into a bus, the passenger needs to swipe the RFID card through which RFID based bus fare payment system will take place. A web application is also developed to monitor the whole system so that this system can ensure the security of the passenger. So, this project emphasizes on minimizing the problems faced by the passengers, drivers and the concerned authority.

• https://github.com/jahidkhandaker/NSUTS



Md Jahid Hasan Khandaker

Full Stack Web Developer



15 Octber 1997



ward 68, DSCC, Tengra, Sarulia, Demra, Dhaka



+8801676123950



github.com/jahidkhandaker



jahid123950@gmail.com

About me -

I would love to involve myself in an organization where I will be able to deliver my skills through my hard work and dedication towards my responsibility. I always try to learn new things to build up my professional skills. In the future, I want to see myself in a place where I can utilize my capabilities to the fullest benefits of the organization and society.

Skills -

OOP (JavaScript, PHP, Java, C++)

HTML, CSS, Bootstrap

React, NodeJS

Laravel Framework

MySQL, MongoDB

Version Control tool (Git, Github)

Microsoft Office(Word, PowerPoint, Excel)

(*)[The skill scale is from 0 (Fundamental Awareness) to 6 (Expert).]

Other Projects

Proshop: E-commerce website using MERN (Build with MongoDB, Express, Reactis, NodeJs)

- · User authentication with JWT, User authentication with JWT
- Add to cart option, Complete Ordering Process with shipping option
- Tracking delivery and payment status
- Admin panel with create delete update product options
- Update delivery and payment status option
- Project link:https://mernappecommerce.herokuapp.com

Emaily: Mass email sending service with feedback survey (Build with MongoDB, Express, Reactjs, NodeJs)

- · Google authentication
- · Create new survey
- · Mass email sender to customers
- · Get customers response
- · Add credit options with card payment
- Project link:ttps://tranguil-forest-81132.herokuapp.com

Visitor Management System (Build with MongoDB, Express, Reactis, NodeJs)

- Visitor and Officer separate authentication with JWT
- · Get All visitor and officers list
- Create appointment by visitor
- · Create instant appointment by officers
- Search appointment by mobile number
- · Assign and cancel access card to visitor
- Change appointment status to approved or reject
- Project link: https://visitormsystem.herokuapp.com

References

· Dr. Shazzad Hosain

Professor

Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering North South University

Email: shazzad.hosain@northsouth.edu

AKM Bahalul Haque

Lecturer

Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering

North South University

Email: bahalul.haque@northsouth.edu